<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dude</title>
    <link>https://www.brichards.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dude</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 10:20:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.brichards.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Books October 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 10:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2019/</guid>
      <description>Alices Adventures in Wonderland by Lewis Carroll Clowns Versus Spiders by Jeff Strand Dances with Dragons by George R.R. Martin The Sorrows by Jonathan Janz Catch and Kill by Ronan Farrow Permanent Record by Edward Snowden Spider-Man: The Darkest Hours by Jim Butcher Caliban&#39;s War by James S.A. Corey  So here were a number of fun books &amp;ndash; definitely had a good month. Clowns Vs. Spiders was a surprise, since I started reading it merely because the title sounded fun and campy, and I should have known that I was in for much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books September 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2019/</guid>
      <description>Starting Strength - Mark Rippatoe Hounded - Kevin Hearne What If? - Randall Munroe The Witcher Sword of Destiny - Andrzej Sapkowski Growing Things - Paul Tremblay The Tools of Titans - Tim Ferris She Said by Jodi Kantor The Art of Invisibility - Kevin Mitnick The Ruins - Scott Smith Nightmares and Dreamscapes volume 1 - Stephen King The Institute - Stephen King  This was a really solid month for books, and there are several here that were stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books August 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of August.
 Click Here to Kill Everybody - Bruce Schneier  The Best American Mystery Stories For We Are Many - Dennis E. Taylor All These Worlds - Dennis E. We Have Always Lived In the Castle - Shirley Jackson Godzilla - King of the Monsters - Greg Keyes The Churn - James S.A. Corey  This was a good month for reading, particularly because I found a few audiobooks that I just absolutely devoured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books July 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of July.
 Stranger Things Darkness on the Edge of Town - Adam Christopher Quiet - Susan Cain I&#39;ll Be Gone in the Dark - Michelle McNamara  I really got swept up in &amp;ldquo;I&#39;ll Be Gone in the Dark.&amp;rdquo; I have not read a whole lot of true crime stuff before, and something that I really appreciated about this was learning so much of McNamara&#39;s personal ups and downs with her investigations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yay, me. ServiceNow Certified System Administrator once again</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/servicenow-sysadmin-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 10:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/servicenow-sysadmin-cert/</guid>
      <description>So earlier today I had a little bit of time to kill because of an instance upgrade, so I decided to retake my ServiceNow Certified System Administrator certification. Which is kind of a mouthful, but it&#39;s just not that important to enough people for there to be a handy acronym like CCNA or SAT.
But it&#39;s important to me, and I passed. Woo!
For people who work on the ServiceNow platform the system administrator certification is the most common shingle to seek, and it demonstrates that I know enough about where all the levers and gears are in ServiceNow to be permitted admin access without everyone else in the organization sweating bullets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books June 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 10:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of June.
 The God Gene - F.Paul Wilson 10% Happier - Dan Harris Castaways - Brian Keene  Not a huge list this month, although these were each really worth the time. This is only natural I suppose since it&#39;s been a long time since I&#39;ve tried to force myself to push through to the end of a clunker. There just seems to be no point in finishing a bad book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books May 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2019/</guid>
      <description>I finished these books during the month of May, 2019.
 Anansi Boys - Neil Gaiman Killer Crabs - Guy N. Smith The Meg - Steve Alten The Consuming Fire - John Scalzi The Necroscope - Brian Lumley Alien III - William Gibson  These books were fantastic. All of them. The reading I did this month reminded me of summers hunkered in my bedroom, sweating from the heat (because we had no air conditioning upstairs in our house) flipping through the grainy pages of books I had scooped up at Waldenbooks in between drooling over the manuals in the Dungeons and Dragons section and walking past the arcade wishing I had the quarters to play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books April 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2019/</guid>
      <description>I finished these books during the month of April, 2019.
 The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business - Charles Duhigg The Little Book of Hygge: Danish Secrets to Happy Living - Meik Wiking The Lost Level - Brian Keene Under the Empyrean Sky - Chuck Wendig The Buddha Walks Into a Bar - Lodro Rinzler  The Power of Habit fascinated me, and it&#39;s a book that I think I might go back to from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books March 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 12:00:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>Leviathan Wakes - James S.A. Corey Tribesmen: A Novella of Supernatural Cannibal Horror - Adam Cesare Fear: Trump in the White House - Bob Woodward No More Mr. Nice Guy - Robert Glover  Leviathan Wakes &amp;ndash; which naturally is the lead off novel of the Expanse series &amp;ndash; certainly lived up to the hype. I was a bit hesitant to get started with because sometimes I just don&#39;t want to start a book that will feel like slog to get through, and often epic space novels are like that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books February 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 01:00:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2019/</guid>
      <description>Books finished during February 2019:
 You Are Here - Thich Nat Hanh Hack: A LitRPG Novel (Tower of Gates Book 1) - Paul Bellow Hunter Hunterson &amp;amp; Sons - Scott Sigler  Pretty light work this month. I had a lot going on with my job, so I was somewhat distracted.
I&#39;ll say this &amp;ndash; I love me some Scott Sigler. He&#39;s somewhat crude, especially in this Hunter Hunterson &amp;amp; Sons volume (which is really just a small collection of short stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books January 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2019/</guid>
      <description>I got 2019 off to a good start by reading the following this month:
 City of Ghosts - V.E. Schwab &amp;lsquo;Salem&#39;s Lot - Stephen King Zen: Beginner&#39;s Guide - Ian Tuhovsky  Seems like kind of a paltry list, but these were good, solid reads.
I make no excuses about City of Ghosts &amp;ndash; it is a young adult book. Fine. Sue me. I have heard so many good things about Schwab&#39;s writing, and I think this story gave me solid proof that the rumors were true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ServiceNow Scoped Applications</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/sn-scoped-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/sn-scoped-apps/</guid>
      <description>#ServiceNow application development notes#
I am hesitant to characterize this as a &amp;lsquo;best practices&amp;rsquo; post or a &amp;lsquo;developer&#39;s guide&amp;rsquo; of any kind, because what I have come to believe after making use of application scope in ServiceNow for the last couple of years is that it is ultimately just another feature of the product. And as such there are many &amp;lsquo;right&amp;rsquo; ways of taking advantage of application scopes for a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For my students: starting off 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/travling-japan-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/travling-japan-2019/</guid>
      <description>Tech things I saw traveling to Japan Since I intend this to be more of a &amp;lsquo;notes to self&amp;rsquo; journal than a personal blog I&#39;m not going to go into a lot of details about the terrific experience my wife and I had while traveling to Japan at the end of 2018. It was beautiful and rewarding, so let&#39;s just leave it at that. What I would like to do is post a few observations about technology from the trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For my students: starting off 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/starting-off-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/starting-off-2019/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in any of my online classes. I post entries in this blog in order to help you succeed in the unique environment of an online college course, which I hope you realize is a lot different than other kinds of classes.
So here we go with a new year. This is the time when everyone is making resolutions and getting pumped up for a new fitness routine, a cleaner house, or maybe a new adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books December 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2019/</guid>
      <description>Full Throttle by Joe Hill The Real Lolita by Weinman
 Visions of Fire &amp;ndash; Gillian Anderson  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books December 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 10:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2018/</guid>
      <description>Alive &amp;ndash; Scott Sigler The Flash: Stop Motion &amp;ndash;  Spinechillers &amp;ndash; various] Doom 2: Hell on Earth - Dafydd an Hugh Elevation - Stephen King The Wizard of Oz - Frank Baum  Okay, so I did not get to read a whole lot this month. In my defense (not that a guy really needs to defend himself on this kind of thing) I have recently started a new job and I also made a long trip to Japan for the holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books November 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 15:27:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2018/</guid>
      <description>Visions of Fire &amp;ndash; Gillian Anderson Solo &amp;ndash; Mur Lafferty Bored and Brilliant &amp;ndash; Manoush Zamorodi A Feast of Crows &amp;ndash; George R.R. Martin  I have to admit to being a little disappointed in the Visions of Fire book from Gillian Anderson. I had been looking forward to reading this for some time, and I found it to be somewhat flighty. A really interesting premise, however, and I will likely give the next book a shot to see where the story goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books November 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 12:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nightmares and Dreamscapes part three by Stephen King Wanderers by Chuck Wendig Daredevil: the Man without Fear by Paul Crilley Earthworm Gods by Brian Keene  Lots of fun stuff this month. It goes without saying that Wanderers by Chuck Wendig was a long, enjoyable ride worth recommending to everyone. The book has been popular since its really, and rightly so. It&#39;s a bit of a hopeful apocalyptic story, but maybe I have a screwed up perspective on the end of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books October 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 15:27:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2018/</guid>
      <description>American Demon Hunters &amp;ndash; J. Thorn Frankenstein: Prodigal Son - Dean Koontz No Sleep til Wonderland &amp;ndash; Paul Tremblay Little Slaughterhoues on the Prairie &amp;ndash; Harold Schecter  I read American Dream Hunters because I participated in a writing workshop (called Night of the Writing Dead) hosted by the author, and I wasn&#39;t disappointed. This isn&#39;t exactly Shirley Jackson, but at the same time it was tightly written and comprised of a very interesting premise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books September 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2018/</guid>
      <description>ServiceNow Developers Handbook - Tim Woodruff Knee-Deep in the Dead - Dafydd ab Hugh Batman Inferno - Alex Irvine Doom 3 - Matthew Costello  It was a pretty thin month for reading this September, but that’s okay. I had fun.
The novelizations for the game Doom were candy-like cheap fun when I read them the first time through, and I digging into Knee-Deep in the Dead took me right back to those days of reading cheap paperbacks while crashed out on a pull-out sofa in my parents’ basement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I just took the Testout Security Pro certification exam</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/testout-security-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/testout-security-cert/</guid>
      <description>And boy am I tired.
Well that&#39;s not entirely true, but the exam took far longer than I had expected.
I am posting this summary for my students at CSU who will be taking this certification test after having completed all the Testout tutorials required for my IST 350 course. Each week the course works methodically through tutorials covering subjects from physical security to perimeter, network, and application issues. We cover very client-specific like completing tasks in Microsoft Group Policy Editor and Cisco switch management, and I suspect not a lot of my students have ever had their hands on these tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books August 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 08:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2018/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of August.
 The Little Sleep - Paul Tremblay The Wolfen - Whitely Strieber Green Lantern Sleepers Book 1 - Christopher Priest The Demon Awakens - R.A. Salvatore The Troop - Nick Cutter Ice Cold: A Rizzoli and Isles Nove - Tess Gerritsen  I thoroughly enjoyed the books I read this month, but the standout title for me has to be Ice Cold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 6 - Network Optimization</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk6-08_06_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk6-08_06_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing tips for my students</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/writingtips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 15:13:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/writingtips/</guid>
      <description>Since I am in the middle of grading a large batch of final papers for a class I feel inspired to write down some tips for my future students (since these tips ain&#39;t helping my current classes.)
You earn your A’s in an online class through writing, plain and simple. Because most hands-on class activities are simply impractical, written papers and online discussion forums take up the bulk of how you’re evaluated in just about every online class, and certainly of every online class I teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books July 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 08:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2018/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of July.
 Any Man - Amber Tamblyn City of the Dead - Brian Keene The Cabin at the End of the World - Paul Tremblay Wonder Woman - Mythos - Carol Lay Thinking in Bets - Annie Duke The Honor of the Queen - David Weber Wayne of Gotham - Tracy Hickman Night of the Crabs - Guy N. Smith Final Crisis - Greg Cox The Hot Zone - Richard Preston  This month I took advantage of Humble Bundle&#39;s DC Comics offering, which included a bunch of audiobooks from Graphic Audio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 5 - Network Management</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk5-07_31_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk5-07_31_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 4 - Wireless Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk4-07_23_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk4-07_23_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 3 - Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk3-07_16_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk3-07_16_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 2 - Ethernet and IP</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk2-07_09_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk2-07_09_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IT 340 WK 2 - Networking Basics and Devices</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk1_07_02_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/it-340-wk1_07_02_2018/</guid>
      <description>Obligatory preamble: This post is intended for students in my&#39;Network and Telecomm Management&amp;rsquo; class, an undergraduate course that covers the core concepts of networking and telecommunications concepts. A key element of this course is the completion of Testout&#39;s Network Pro set of online tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the one about why I made this blog in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/whytheblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/whytheblog/</guid>
      <description>It seems that every blog (online diary, journal, self-loving website, etc) that I run across that has been redesigned in Hugo has a post early on about why it was redesigned in Hugo. This seems like a weird thing to do in the wide world of the web, since people are constantly changing the underlying technologies of their website without wasting a lot of time talking about it, but in my case Ima going to do that thing because there is a point to be made about why I have taken the time to do something other than Wordpress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books June 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 13:40:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2018/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of June.
 Lolita - Vladmir Nabokov The Last Jedi - Jason Fry Red Rain - R.L. Stine Zeroes - Chuck Wending The Outsider - Stephen King The Old Man and the Sea - Ernest Hemingway  So I was never an R.L. Stine guy, having been born about a decade late to really appreciate his books when I was the right age for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books May 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 15:13:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2018/</guid>
      <description>The following were books I finished reading during the month of May.
 Jurassic Park - Michael Crichton Fahrenheit 451 - Ray Bradbury Something Wicked This Way Comes - Ray Bradbury Pet Semetery - Stephen King The Long Way to a Small, Angry Planet (Wayfarers) Casino Royale - Ian Fleming From Russia With Love - Ian Fleming A Clockwork Orange - Anthony Burgess Quiet - Susan Cain  What I discoverd this month was that Ian Fleming is a really fun writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books April 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 15:20:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2018/</guid>
      <description>I finished these books during the month of April, 2018.
 Siddhartha - Hermann Hesse Aftermath: Empire&#39;s End - Chuck Wendig Dust and Decay - Johnathan Maberry Damn Fine Story - Chuck Wendig  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books March 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 15:21:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2018/</guid>
      <description>Aided by a little extra travel time this month, here are the books I finished reading during March, 2018.
 Alien - River of Pain - Christopher Golden Great Gatsby - F Scott Fitzgerald V-Wars - Jonathan Maberry The Handmaid&#39;s Tale - Margaret Atwood V-Wars - Johnathan Maberry Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep - Philip K. Dick No Middle Name - Lee Child City of Endless Night - Preston and Child So good they can&#39;t ignore you - Cal Newport  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books February 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 15:23:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2018/</guid>
      <description>Books finished during February 2018:
 At the Mountains of Madness - H.P. Lovecraft Rats - James Herbert The Witches of Lychford - Paul Cornell Flowers for Algernon - Daniel Keyes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Scheier&#39;s Cryptogram</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/cryptogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 15:13:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/cryptogram/</guid>
      <description>Those who have had me for class before have seen this post before.
An important part of every IT professional’s job is continuing education. For the most part we see this as attending conferences and signing up for classes related to new technologies, but one of the simplest (and cheapest) things is to simply stay informed. For anyone in this field, but infosec professionals in particular, Bruce Schneier’s Crypto-gram newsletter is an invaluable source of information about current events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citing Sources in academic papers</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/citingsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 15:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/citingsources/</guid>
      <description>When should you cite your sources?
There are two reasons, for the most part, where a writer should say to himself or herself, “Hey, I should make sure I cite some references here.” The first and most important reason is a deliberate choice you’ve made to back up your own writing with someone else’s writing in order to make it clear that not only did you have a good idea, but your good idea can be supported by reading someone else’s thoughts on the subject you&#39;re talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books January 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 15:24:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2018/</guid>
      <description>I got 2018 off to a good start by reading the following this month:
 Atlanta Burns The Hunt - Chuck Wendig 7 Habits of Highly Effective People - Stephen Covey The Strangest Secret - Earl Nightingale Skeleton Crew - Stephen King The Hematophages - Stephen Kozeniewski Invasive - Chuck Wendig How to Write Pulp Fiction - James Scott Bell We Are Legion - Dennis Taylor Artemis - Andrew Weir The Maltese Falcon - Dashiell Hammet  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books December 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 15:28:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-december-2017/</guid>
      <description>Over time I have owned both a hardcover copy and the audio-cassette version of From a Buick 8, yet I&#39;ve never finished it. The story is set in Western Pennsylvania here and throws a local bone out every once in a while, but the premise of it all is genuinely fascinating. A kind of totem of the kind of cross-universe fantasy Stephen King has introduced in so many of his books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books November 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 15:28:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-november-2017/</guid>
      <description>Each of these books brought its own enjoyment, but it was Joe Hill&#39;s Stange Weather that really got my imagination going. These stories took me away like a gripping episode of the Outer Limits. I feel like an asshole that I have not found anyone to recommend this book to yet.
 Burnt Offerings - Robert Morasco Alone - Scott Sigler Z-Burbia - Jake Bible Atlanta Burns - Chuck Wendig The Fold - Peter Clines Mockingbird - Chuck Wendig Agent to the Stars - John Scalzi Astrophysics for People in a Hurry - Neil deGrasse Tyson Strange Weather - Joe Hill  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books October 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 15:27:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-october-2017/</guid>
      <description>This was actually a pretty heavy month of reading, and there were two books here I would gladly revisit. Sleeping Beauties carried me through a whole world, very much in the flavor of other Stephen King books. His collaboration with his son is really enjoyable storytelling.
And then there is the Tomb. Wilson&#39;s story has all the ingredients for a meaty thriller, and it&#39;s a good justification for me to push into the rest of his books, which I know includes the really well regarded Repairman Jack series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books September 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 15:27:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-september-2017/</guid>
      <description>More Chuck Wendig, thankyouverymuch.
 Alien: Bug Hunt- Jonathan Maberry X-Files: Cold Cases Blackbirds - Chuck Wendig  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books August 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 15:27:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-august-2017/</guid>
      <description>That&#39;s all. Just the one. But it was a doozy.
 Frankenstorm - Ray Gartnon  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books July 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 15:27:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>This is where I became a fan of Chuck Wendig. All the books, but starting with Aftermath and his thoroughly enjoyable take on the Star Wars canon.
Aftermath - Chuck Wendig The Piper - Ben Miller Rot and Ruin - Jonathan Mayberry Just Like Hell / Mr Gray - Nate Southard</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books June 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 15:27:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-june-2017/</guid>
      <description> Hillbilly Elegy - JD Vance Gwendy&#39;s Button Box - Stephen King and Richard Chizmar Ararat - Christopher Golden Antorkis Rising - Jeremy Robinson Dark Matter- Blake Crouch  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books May 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 15:27:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-may-2017/</guid>
      <description> The Exorcist - William Peter Blatty Half Way Home - Hugh Howey Falling Angel - William Hjortsberg  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk07_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk07_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk07_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk06_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk06_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk06_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books April 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 15:27:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>Again, not much in the way of notes here, but I will say that Deep Work really had an impact on how I think about my approach to working from day to day. I took it on as kind of twisted book club reading the CMU Alumni association, and while I never got to chat about it with any of my fellow Tartans, I truly enjoyed the reading.
Deep Work - Cal Newport F*ck Feelings - Michael Bennet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk05_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk05_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk05_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk04_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk04_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk04_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk03_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk03_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk03_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk02_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk02_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk02_04_2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its 350 Wk01_04_2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk01_04_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-350-wk01_04_2017/</guid>
      <description>ITS 350 Week One This post is intended for students in my ITS 350 Introduction to Computer Security course at Colorado State University. The majority of information related to the course is available within the course online, but I try to provide additional material like this week in order to bring my own experiences / web surfings / questions about the subject out into the open without diluting what the school has prepared in terms of course materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ITS 360 Week One 12_2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/its-360-wk01_12_2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/its-360-wk01_12_2019/</guid>
      <description>ITS 350 Week One This post is intended for students in my ITS 350 Introduction to Computer Security course at Colorado State University. The majority of information related to the course is available within the course online, but I try to provide additional material like this week in order to bring my own experiences / web surfings / questions about the subject out into the open without diluting what the school has prepared in terms of course materials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books March 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 15:27:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-march-2017/</guid>
      <description>F it &amp;ndash; I don&#39;t have detailed notes on these, but I enjoyed them. Silence of the Lambs was far better than I expected, and as much because the movie followed it so closely as anything.
 Callsign Bishop - Jeremy Robinson Pulse - Jeremy Robinson Silence of the Lambs - Thomas Harris Turn of the Screw - Henry James Abandon - Blake Crouch Unmasking Narcissism - Mark Ettensohn  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books February 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 15:27:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-february-2017/</guid>
      <description>Joe Haldeman. Damn. The Forever War was a terrific read.
I&#39;ll also say that I don&#39;t know of anyone who reads Jeremy Robinson, but his books are a blast. I particularly like the kaiju ones, but they&#39;re all fun, fast reads.
 Welcome to Maplecroft - Cherie Priest Disappearance at Devil&#39;s Rock - Paul Tremblay Island 731 - Jeremy Robinson The Forever War - Joe Haldeman  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books January 2017</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 15:27:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/books-january-2017/</guid>
      <description>I never read Terry Brooks back in high school when I was, you know, scheduled to do so by way of my active participation in the girl-less nerds of D&amp;amp;D club. I really missed out, so now I am burdened with having to dig through these beautiful, thick, well worn books as an adult. Darn.
 Sword of Shannara - Terry Brooks Panacea - F. Paul Wilson The Subtle Art of Not Giving a Fuck - Mark Manson the Life Changing Magic of Tidying Up - Marie Kondo  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this guy</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/about/</guid>
      <description>Brian has nearly twenty years of experience as a member of operations teams at Penn State University and Carnegie Mellon University in roles such as developer, system administrator, SAN administrator, and IT manager. Brian is currently contributing to a team supporting ServiceNow, a cloud-based IT Service Management platform, for CMU. At the same time he has been teaching courses in technology at several universities both on ground and online.
Brian has earned two Master’s degrees: one in instructional technology and one in information technology security and assurance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>