<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Student on Brian Richards and his stuff</title>
    <link>https://www.brichards.net/tags/student/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Student on Brian Richards and his stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 15:13:07 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.brichards.net/tags/student/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing tips for my students</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/post/writingtips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 15:13:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/post/writingtips/</guid>
      <description>Since I am in the middle of grading a large batch of final papers for a class I feel inspired to write down some tips for my future students (since these tips ain&amp;rsquo;t helping my current classes.)
You earn your A’s in an online class through writing, plain and simple. Because most hands-on class activities are simply impractical, written papers and online discussion forums take up the bulk of how you’re evaluated in just about every online class, and certainly of every online class I teach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Scheier&#39;s Cryptogram</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/post/cryptogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 15:13:07 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/post/cryptogram/</guid>
      <description>Those who have had me for class before have seen this post before.
An important part of every IT professional’s job is continuing education. For the most part we see this as attending conferences and signing up for classes related to new technologies, but one of the simplest (and cheapest) things is to simply stay informed. For anyone in this field, but infosec professionals in particular, Bruce Schneier’s Crypto-gram newsletter is an invaluable source of information about current events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citing Sources in academic papers</title>
      <link>https://www.brichards.net/post/citingsources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 15:09:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brichards.net/post/citingsources/</guid>
      <description>When should you cite your sources?
There are two reasons, for the most part, where a writer should say to himself or herself, “Hey, I should make sure I cite some references here.” The first and most important reason is a deliberate choice you’ve made to back up your own writing with someone else’s writing in order to make it clear that not only did you have a good idea, but your good idea can be supported by reading someone else’s thoughts on the subject you&amp;rsquo;re talking about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>